ALEXANDER HILL

Alexandria, VA 22314 • email@alexanderhill.us • https://www.ahresume.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Accomplished Desktop Engineer experienced in Microsoft Windows Administration, Task Automation, Application Packaging and Deployment, and Workstation Compliance. Extensive knowledge of BigFix, Microsoft Deployment Toolkit, PowerShell, and Enterprise Device Management. All of these have been used to markedly improve the efficiency of Windows workstation administration in the environment.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Microsoft 365 Certified: Modern Desktop Administrator Associate, Microsoft September 2022
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900), Microsoft December 2022
- ITIL Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management, Exin February 2013

SKILLS

- Microsoft Windows
- HCL BigFix
- Application Deployment
- Microsoft Intune
- Microsoft Endpoint Manager (MEM)
- Microsoft 365
- Group Policy
- Active Directory
- Azure Active Directory
- Microsoft Deployment Toolkit (MDT)
- Powershell Scripting
- Mobile Device Management
- Desktop Administration
- Troubleshooting
- Configuration Management

WORK HISTORY

Desktop Engineer

GRSI, National Institutes of Health - Bethesda, MD

07/2021 - Current

Responsible for administering over 3,500 Windows Endpoints using tools such as HCL BigFix, Powershell, Remote Desktop Protocol, and Bomgar Remote Support. In charge of running the MDT server to manage three (3) Windows Workstation Images. Create automation scripts to support projects and administrative tasks as needed

- Wrote PowerShell scripts to automate the migration of data of over 2,000 users from their home shares to OneDrive
- · Created custom application packages for deployment through BigFix as well as manual installation
- Developed tools to streamline common tasks for workstation administration and analysis including Active Directory tasks, BIOS Configuration, and Registry settings for Local and Remote Usage
- Created tasks to automate driver management in MDT, significantly reducing the time and effort required to maintain the latest drivers on the Deployment Share
- Wrote script to remediate Log4j vulnerabilities in the environment causing a 93% drop over the summer of 2022

- Utilized Powershell to analyze vulnerability and compliance data from Tenable Security Center, then generate reports for other teams
- Quickly set up BigFix Fixlets and Analyses to deploy multiple Security Agents to workstations by a shortened deadline and monitor their status

SYSTEMS ENGINEER

GDIT, National Institutes of Health - Bethesda, MD

12/2019 - 07/2021

Focused on using BigFix to improve the security compliance of Endpoints. Managed the Imaging environment utilizing the Microsoft Deployment Toolkit. Also supported desktop technicians with escalations and streamlining common tasks

- Responsible for using BigFix to test and install Windows patches to workstations in accordance with the maintenance cycle
- Created custom scripts and Bigfix jobs as needed to install Third-Party applications with customized install settings
- Developed scripts that desktop technicians could use to check and set BIOS settings on workstations
- Testing various hardware configurations to ensure compatibility in the environment
- Manage Windows Workstation Images using MDT
- Wrote or modified documentation involving Patching and Maintenance procedures for the environment.

SYSTEMS TECHNICIAN III

GDIT, National Institutes of Health - Bethesda, MD

05/2018 - 12/2019

Served as OIT Desktop Team Lead for the Main Campus Location as well as being the primary support for Executive Officer and staff

- Trusted to provide exceptional support for Office of the Director (OD) staff at the Main Campus location
- Functioned as an escalation point for desktop technicians
- Trained new technicians as they were onboarded to the team
- Greatly improved workstation replacement efficiency with scripts to backup and user data
- Able to successfully develop process to verify over 2,000 workstations for a vendor recall project
- Authored Standards of Procedure, Work Instructions and other documentation

Senior Desktop Support Technician

XA Systems, National Institutes of Health - Bethesda, MD

09/2012 - 05/2018

Started as a Mid-Level Desktop Technician and promoted to Senior-Level supporting Windows Endpoints

- Resolved variety of Windows support issues including software such as Office, hardware troubleshooting and network connectivity issues
- Trusted to handle VIP service requests in a timely and efficient manner
- Used Bomgar Support Tool for assisting customers remotely
- Worked with network operations team to maintain the Windows workstation images using MDT
- Developed into Senior level technician and reliable resource for coworkers and VIP support

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: Electrical Engineering Technology, Computer Science **OLD DOMINION UNIVERSITY** - Norfolk, VA